[Music]
oh this hard time to get off the road
first welcome to the 2023 edition of
autox awards now this year marks our
17th anniversary and of course as always
we are going to celebrate it with a bank
and as a result we have got some hot new
medal to test for our best of 2023
Awards so what you see behind me are 13
all new bikes and a scooter which we are
going to be testing at the IAT test
track facility so let's get going and
take a look at all the bikes and scooter
that we have got here and let's find out
if we can make out which one is going to
win the
[Music]
award
1 so let's take a close look at what all
is available for us to test today now
let's start with the smallest bike or
two wheeler or scooter that we have got
here so this is the hero Zoom of course
it looks very trendy very stylish and I
think it is a great scooter but uh let's
find out if it has more to offer other
than sharp greases and this alien-ish
headlamp of course it's a great scooter
but we'll find out more in a few minutes
time now uh next up we have got the
Honda shine now this is 100c honest to
God motorcycle Honda launched it earlier
this year it is again a very bare basic
motorcycle but again there's nothing
wrong with it so let's see how it fars
in this test now next up there is an
interesting motorcycle this is the
Charisma which is making a comeback and
it's called the XMR of course it looks
fantastic it has got a great engine as
well but compared to all the other
Rivals here how does it fair well we are
going to ride it around this test track
so let's find out if this Charisma is as
sporty as it
looks then we have got the Triumph Speed
400 now this I think is the biggest
launch of the year because with this
motorcycle well they have completely
changed the market for entry level 300
400 60 motorcycles because at the price
that it's launched at well I think it is
very tempting and it is a great
motorcycle of course but again the
question remains is it the best launch
of the year is it as good as it's
cracked up to be well today is the day
when we'll find that out so there is a
motorcycle that I think will make it to
the top or near the top because I have
High Hopes from this motorcycle now next
up you've got its rival this is the
Harley-Davidson x440 now again a very
interesting motorcycle this is hary's
first entrylevel single cylinder
motorcycle that has been launched in
India it's made in partnership with hero
but uh this motorcycle it feeds harly in
everywhere small miniature H you can
call that but again we have to see where
it fits in the market because there are
so many rivals now in the sense the
speed 400 is there and then there is
Royal and field as well but this
motorcycle I think it is quite unique
and it has got that Harley badge which
is going to work in its favor plus it's
also pric re really well now next up we
have got another interesting motorcycle
now this is uh the TVs Apache RDR 310 of
course a very familiar package we have
seen this platform being used multiple
times you've got the Apache R 310 we've
got the BMW g310 so this you'll think
that this is a motorcycle that has the
same recipe but that's not the case
because it offers a lot more it has a
lot more features you've got cooled
seats its engine performance is totally
different different the way this engine
is tuned it is a bit of a hooligan but
again in terms of pricing in terms of
where it's positioned on the market it
also has many rivals which can give it a
run for its money and one of those
Rivals is of course the KTM 390 Duke now
this motorcycle is a complete new
generation it has got a bigger engine
than before that means it's more
powerful it has got a lot of electronics
as well and this is a complete package
for sure of course the prices have gone
up so we have to see if the price is
Justified here or not but I think if you
talk about a complete package like I
said the KTM does everything and now it
also looks like a bigger bike so it has
got that presence as well but what we've
got here is something totally different
now this may look like another Street
naked but the fact of the matter is it's
not an ice engine in the sense it's not
powered by petrol this is all electric
motorcycle and this is the first time
that we going to be riding a performance
electric vehicle so again I have got
high hopes from this motorcycle because
it's going to compete against the likes
of the KTM 390 duke or the TVs Apache
RTR 310 but uh this is electric so how
does it feel compared to an old school
I'm calling it old school I'm sorry but
uh compared to a traditional motorcycle
so this is a very interesting
proposition let's see if it can match
Legacy automakers in terms of what it
brings to the table next up we have got
super meteor 650 again a very
interesting motorcycle a completely new
take the quality levels on this
motorcycle are brilliant of course the
engine and platform is more or less the
same as the Continental GT 650 or the
Interceptor that you've already seen but
this motorcycle for Royal Enfield I
think it takes the game forward because
in every dimension in terms of quality
in terms of fit and finish in terms of
refinement I think this is a great
motorcycle of course it has its flaws
and we'll talk about them in detail
later but I think as a cruiser as a
super Cruiser at that price point I
think it is a great
motorcycle now let's move to big bikes
and we've got some really amazing
motorcycles with us first of all is the
ducatti monster SP it looks like the
same monster that we featured earlier
but in essence this is a totally
different motorcycle everything on this
motorcycle has been completely changed
apart from the engine and the chassis
but it has got all new oin suspension it
has got more Electronics it is beefier
than your regular monster and it is very
aggressive and it feels purpose built
for the racetrack or for someone who
wants to push their motorcycles take
them on a track day so it feels
completely different to a standard
monster I think this is the biggest
difference between a standard monster
and the SV because that SP thing it
definitely brings that ducatti formula
for speed for performance for handling
and I think this marks a huge difference
compared to the regular monster so I'm
really looking forward to push this
motorcycle on a RAC Tack and see how
different is it compared to your regular
monster or is it all on
[Music]
paper the other motorcycle that we have
got here in terms of performance well
it's the s000 RR it is the Big Daddy of
ler glass motorcycles and I think in
this new iteration it looks absolutely
menacing These Wings over here has got
all the downforce it has got the best
electronics that you can find on a liter
class motorcycle and this is a BMW s000
RR it's a sweet handling motorcycle and
I think there's nothing really wrong
with it to be very Frank apart from the
price probably but again we have to test
it because we have got one award for
Performance Bike of the a so whichever
bike laps the circuit in the shortest
time that wins the Performance Bike of
the air it's straightforward and I think
the s000 RR is going to shine in this
department because in terms of power and
performance it's 200 B h plus it is
going to absolutely nail that I'm
thinking it's a wild guess and a
straightforward guess I think this is
going to back the Performance Bike of
there unless something happens but again
we have got another great motorcycle it
is the all new ducatti diaval V4 now
this time diav it used to be a par
Cruiser earlier it had an L2 engine but
now with this all new engine theat has
completely changed that formula they've
completely changed the dimension they
have completely changed the definition
of power cruising because this one it
has got a super bike chassis it has got
a super bike engine it comes with the V4
engine now as the name suggests and if
you ride it around you'll notice that it
feels very agile it feels very light it
doesn't feel like a cruiser so again
they have completely redefined the
segment and I'm looking forward to ride
this motorcycle on the track as well
because the last time we rode the DI uh
the 1261 I think it felt a little
cumbersome but this when I rode it
around today around the track I thought
it it was very Nimble and I think it's
also very refined so again it has a high
price strike but what it brings to the
table well of course it's unmatched by
any other Cruiser or power Cruiser in
that segment now last but not least
we've got another ducatti and I think
this is the most fun motorcycle here
because this is the ducatti desert X now
this was launched late last year it
qualifies for our Awards this year but
what a funl looking motorcycle you just
have to look at it once and you realize
that it is going to be fun everywhere
you just have to look at this motorcycle
look at these knobby tires look at the
suspension travel look at that face of
this motorcycle it looks like it's meant
for just one thing that is fun and I
also think it has got a lot of X Factor
because of that paint Scheme because of
that ducatti badge and because the way
it looks so I think as a fun motorcycle
it has got a lot to offer plus that
engine also has a lot more character it
is suited for off-road riding it is very
Snappy but again we have to put it to
test today thoroughly to see if it can
be one of the best of 2023 Award winners
so this is the lineup that we have got
here we are going to be testing all of
these bikes at the test track today so
uh three bikes are going to be winning
the award which is best of 2023 so these
are the top three bikes and of course
like I said earlier there is going to be
one award for the Performance Bike of
the year so all of that is coming to you
very soon because we are going to be
riding and testing these motorcycles so
stay tuned to autox to watch the
complete Jewelry round which is headed
your way very very
[Music]
soon
n